《哈利波特与凤凰社》
I don't know about you, it's just too hot today, isn't it?
不知道你怎么看 不过今天确实太热了，不是吗？
And it's going to get even worse. Temperatures up in the mid- 30s Celsius...
而且还有更热的趋势 未来几天气温将达到摄氏30度以上
...that's the mid- 90s Fahrenheit, tomorrow, maybe even hitting 100.
也就是华氏90度以上 明天甚至可能达到华氏100度
So, please, remember to cover up and stay cool...
所以，请记得找个凉快的地方
...with the hottest hits on your FM dial.
收听FM调频广播的最热门评论
Come on, guys, time to go home.
来吧，孩子，该回家了
Come on, love, off you get.
快，亲爱的，快起来
- Do we have to? - Yes, we do.
- 一定要吗？ - 当然
I'll make you your favorite dinner to compensate.
我会准备你最爱吃的晚餐来补偿的
He squealed like a pig, didn't he?
他叫起来就像头猪，不是吗？
Yeah, brilliant punch, Big D. Did you see his face?
是啊，打得太有形了，大迪 你看到他的脸了吗？
Hey, Big D.
喂！大迪
Beat up another 10- year-old?
又在欺负10岁小孩了？
- This one deserved it. - Yeah.
- 他活该 - 没错
- Five against one, very brave. - Well, you're one to talk.
- 五对一，你可真勇敢 - 这话轮不到你说
Moaning in your sleep every night? At least I'm not afraid of my pillow.
每晚睡着了还在嘀咕 起码我不会被自己的枕头吓倒
"Don't kill Cedric."
“别杀塞德里克”
Who's Cedric, your boyfriend?
塞德里克是谁？你男朋友？
- Shut up. - "He's going to kill me, Mum."
- 住口 - “他要杀我，妈妈！”
Where is your mum?
你妈呢？
Where is your mum, Potter?
你妈在哪里啊，波特？
She dead?
死了？
Is she dead?
死了吧？
Is she a dead Pott...
是死了吧，波...
- Dudley. - Dudley, let's go.
- 达力 - 达力，我们走
- What's going on? - What are you doing?
- 发生什么事了？ - 你在做什么？
- I'm not doing anything. - We're getting out of here, Dudley.
- 我什么也没做 - 我们走吧，达力
Come on, Dudley, hurry up.
来吧，达力，快点
Dudley, run.
达力，快跑
Expecto Patronum.
呼神护卫
Mrs. Figg.
费格太太
Don't put away your wand, Harry.
别把魔杖收起来，哈利
They might come back.
他们可能还会回来
Dementors in Little Whinging, whatever next?
摄魂怪出现在小文金镇 接下来会是什么？
- Whole world's gone topsy-turvy. - I don't understand. How do you know...
- 整个世界都乱七八糟的 - 我不明白，你怎么知道?
Dumbledore asked me to keep an eye on you.
邓布利多叫我看着你
Dumbledore asked you? You know Dumbledore?
邓布利多？ 你认识邓布利多？
After You- Know- Who killed that poor Diggory boy last year...
去年可怜的迪戈里被神秘人杀死后
...did you expect him to let you go wandering on your own?
你以为他还会让你一个人到处晃？
Good Lord, boy. They told me you were intelligent.
天啊，哈利 他们告诉我你很聪明的
Now, get inside and stay there.
从现在起，到里面去 呆在那！
Expect someone will be in touch soon. Whatever happens, don't leave the house.
很快就会有人联系你的 不管发生什么事，别出来
It is hot. That's right, hot everywhere.
是很热，没错，到处都很热
There's sweat. There's stifling.
简直就是汗流浃背，太闷了
Diddykins?
小达？
Is that you?
是你吗？
Duddy. Vernon, come quick.
达力！弗农，快过来！
We're going to have to take him to a hospital.
我们得带他去医院
Who did this to you, boy?
是谁做的，孩子？
Happy, are we, now?
你现在高兴了吧？
You've finally done it. You've finally driven him loopy.
你总算如愿以偿了 你总算是把他给弄傻了
Vernon, don't say that.
弗农，别说了
Well, just look at him, Petunia. Our boy has gone yumpy.
你看看这孩子，佩妮 我们的孩子傻了
I've reached my limit, do you hear?
我已经忍无可忍了，听到了吗？
This is the last I'm gonna take of you and your nonsense.
这是我最后一次容忍你这种行为
- Dear Mr. Potter. - What?
- 亲爱的波特先生 - 什么？
The Ministry has received intelligence that at 6:23 this evening...
魔法部得到消息 在今晚的6点23分
...you performed the Patronus Charm in the presence of a Muggle.
你曾在一位麻瓜面前 使用了守护神魔咒
As a clear violation...
此行为违反了...
...of the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage Sorcery...
禁止未成年巫师使用魔法条例
...you are hereby expelled...
因此，你已被驱逐出...
...from Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
霍格沃茨魔法学院
Hoping you are well, Mafalda Hopkirk.
愿一切安好，马法尔达·霍普柯克
Justice.
天理啊
He's not very well.
他有些不舒服
Sorry, Hedwig.
对不起，海德薇
Very clean, these Muggles.
这些人还真爱干净
- Tonks, for God's sake. - Unnatural.
- 唐克斯，拜托 - 太不自然了
Professor Moody.
穆迪教授
- What are you doing here? - Rescuing you, of course.
- 你来这里做什么？ - 当然是来救你
But where are we going? The letter said I've been expelled.
我们能去哪儿？ 那封信说我已经被退学了
You haven't been. Not yet. Kingsley, you take point.
不，目前还没有 金斯莱，你挑点重点说
But the letter said...
但信上说...
Dumbledore persuaded the minister to suspend your expulsion...
邓布利多说服了魔法部的人 等开个正式的听证会后...
- ...pending a formal hearing. - A hearing?
- 才决定是否让你退学 - 听证会？
Don't worry. We'll explain everything when we get back to headquarters.
别担心，我们到了总部再解释给你听
Not here, Nymphadora.
别在这里说，尼法朵拉
Don't call me Nymphadora.
不要叫我尼法朵拉
Stay in formation, everyone. Don't break ranks if one of us is killed.
大家一定得保持队形 即使有人被杀了也别掉队
Come on, you, around the corner.
快点，你，在拐角的
Come on.
快
In you go, son.
进去，孩子
There've been no sightings.
那里没有任何证人
No deaths. No proof.
没有死亡，没有证据
He almost killed Harry. If that isn't proof enough...
他差点儿就杀了哈利 如果证据不够充分...
Yes, but guarding you- know- what is the most important...
是的，但是保护那个最重要的是...
We must trust Dumbledore on this.
我们得相信邓布利多
Was he able to protect Harry last year? Well, tonight I say it's time to take action.
他去年保护哈利了吗？ 嗯，我认为今晚就该采取行动了
Cornelius Fudge is a politician first and a wizard second.
康奈利·福吉首先是个政治家 其次才能算个巫师
- His instinct would be to ignore it... - Keep your voices down.
- 他的本能会忽略掉... - 拜托，声音小点
He's getting stronger and stronger by the minute. We have to act now.
他变得越来越强大了 我们得赶快行动
- Harry. - Mrs. Weasley.
- 哈利 - 韦斯莱太太
Heavens, you're all right.
谢天谢地，你没事
Bit peaky, but I'm afraid dinner will wait until after the meeting's finished.
瘦了点 但晚餐恐怕得等开完会才能吃
Nope. No time to explain. Straight upstairs, first door on the left.
不，现在没时间解释 到楼上去，左边第一扇门
Yeah.
对
Mudblood, werewolves, traitors, thieves.
泥巴种，狼人，叛徒，小偷
If my poor mistress knew the scum they let into her house...
我可怜的女主人 他们都带了什么垃圾到她家里来
...what would she say to old Kreacher?
她会对克利切怎么说？
Oh, the shame.
哦，真是可耻
- Freaks. - There, there, mistress.
- 都是些畸形人 - 到处都是，女主人
Scum of the earth. Not like it was in the days of my fathers.
地球上的垃圾 再也不像父亲他们那段时光了
Kreacher is here.
克利切在这
Oh, Harry.
哦，哈利
Are you all right? We overheard them talking about the Dementor attack.
你没事吧？ 听他们说你被摄魂怪攻击了
- You must tell us everything. - Let the man breathe, Hermione.
- 你得把一切都告诉我们 - 先让他喘口气吧，赫敏
And this hearing at the Ministry. It's just outrageous.
还有魔法部的听证会 太不可理喻了
I've looked it up. They simply can't expel you.
我查过资料 他们根本不能让你退学
- It's completely unfair. - Yeah.
- 这太不公平 - 就是
There's a lot of that going round at the moment.
现在不公平的事可多着呢
So, what is this place?
这是哪里？
- It's headquarters. - Of the Order of the Phoenix.
- 是总部 - 凤凰社的
It's a secret society.
是个秘密组织
Dumbledore formed it back when they fought You- Know- Who.
是邓布利多在上次反抗神秘人时创立的
Couldn't have put any of this in a letter, I suppose?
我猜这些在信里都不能提，是吧？
I've gone all summer without a scrap of news.
我整个夏天就没得到一点消息
We wanted to write, mate. Really, we did.
我们想写的，伙计，是真的
- Only... - Only what?
- 只是... - 只是什么？
Only Dumbledore made us swear not to tell you anything.
只不过邓布利多要我们发誓 不会告诉你任何事
Dumbledore said that?
邓布利多说的？
But why would he keep me in the dark? Maybe I could help.
他为什么要瞒着我？ 也许我还能帮上点忙
I'm the one who saw Voldemort return...
是我看着伏地魔回来的
...the one who fought him, who saw Cedric Diggory get killed.
跟他决斗的人是我 看着塞德里克·迪戈里被杀的人也是我
- Harry. - Thought we heard your dulcet tones.
- 哈利 - 果然是你的声音
- Don't bottle it up, though, mate. Let it out. - Lf you're all done shouting...
- 有什么事别放在心里，伙计，说出来 - 如果你已经发泄完了
Do you wanna hear something a little more interesting?
你想不想听点有趣的事？
If anyone has a right to know, it's Harry. If it wasn't for Harry...
如果有谁有权利知道这件事情，就是哈利 如果不是他...
...we wouldn't even know voldemort was back.
我们根本不知道伏地魔又回来了
He's not a child, Molly.
他已经不是个孩子了，莫丽
But he's not an adult either.
但他也还不是个大人
- He's not James, Sirius. - Well, he's not your son.
- 他不是詹姆，小天狼星 - 嗯，他不是你的儿子
He's as good as.
跟我儿子没两样
- Who else has he got? - Hey, Ginny.
- 除了我以外，他还有谁？ - 嗨，金妮
- He's got me. - How touchingly paternal, Black.
- 他还有我 - 真是感人的父爱啊，布莱克
Perhaps Potter will grow up to be a felon, just like his godfather.
可能波特到时候会跟他教父一样邪恶
Now, you stay out of this, Snivellus.
这里没你的事，西弗勒斯
- Snape's part of the Order? - Git.
- 斯内普也是社员之一？ - 饭桶
About your supposed reformation.
关于你想像的改革
- I know better. - So why don't you tell him?
- 我的想像更好 - 那为什么不跟他说？
- Get off it. - Ouick.
- 放手 - 快点
- Get it up. - Crookshanks.
- 把它放下 - 克鲁克山
- Stop it. - Get off, you bloody cat.
- 住手 - 放手，你这爱偷腥的猫
- Crookshanks. Leave it alone. - Get it up.
- 克鲁克山，别碰它 - 把它放下
- Hermione, I hate your cat. - Bad Crookshanks.
- 赫敏，我讨厌你的猫 - 坏克鲁克山
Well, we'll be eating down in the kitchen.
我们会在厨房吃饭
Just because you're allowed to use magic now...
虽然说你们现在可以用魔法了
...does not mean you have to whip your wands out for everything.
但这不表示每件事 都得拿魔杖出来到处耍
Hi, Mum.
嗨，妈
You hungry, Harry?
饿了吗，哈利？
You sure you're all right, Harry? Gave us quite a turn.
确定没事吧，哈利？ 你把我们吓了一大跳
Harry Potter.
哈利·波特
Sirius.
小天狼星
This is very, very peculiar.
这真是，真是太奇怪了
It seems your hearing in the Ministry is to be before the entire Wizengamot.
似乎你的听证会将在 整个威森加摩面前举行
I don't understand. What has the Ministry of Magic got against me?
我不懂，魔法部为什么这么仇视我
Show him. He'll find out soon enough.
给他看吧，他很快就会发现的
(预言家日报 撒谎的男孩？)
He's been attacking Dumbledore as well.
另外他还在攻击邓布利多
(福吉: 万事皆顺)
Fudge is using all his power, including his influence at the Daily Prophet...
福吉利用了他一切的权力 包括他对预言家日报的影响力
...to smear anyone who claims the Dark Lord has returned.
攻击每一个号称神秘人已回来的人
Why?
为什么？
He thinks Dumbledore's after his job.
他以为邓布利多想抢他饭碗
No one in their right mind could believe that...
这太不可理喻了 正常人都不会认为邓布利多...
Exactly the point. Fudge isn't in his right mind.
就是这个意思 福吉现在不正常
It's been twisted and warped by fear.
他的思想被恐惧控制了
Now, fear makes people do terrible things, Harry.
恐惧是会让人做出很恐怖的事的，哈利
The last time Voldemort gained power...
伏地魔在上次得到力量时
...he almost destroyed everything we hold most dear.
他几乎毁灭了一切我们所珍惜的东西
Now he's returned, and I'm afraid the minister will do almost anything...
现在他回来了 恐怕魔法部长正在尽一切所能...
...to avoid facing that terrifying truth.
否认这个恐怖的事实
We think Voldemort wants to build up his army again.
我们猜想 伏地魔可能在制造自己的军团
Fourteen years ago, he had huge numbers at his command.
十四年前，有一大堆的人听命于他
And not just witches and wizards, but all manner of dark creatures.
不只是巫师和女巫 还包括所有黑暗生物
He's been recruiting heavily, and we've been attempting to do the same.
他正在大肆招兵买马 而我们也是
But gathering followers isn't the only thing he's interested in.
但寻找随从并不是他唯一的目的
We believe...
我们相信...
...Voldemort may be after something.
伏地魔可能在寻找某样东西
Sirius.
小天狼星
Something he didn't have last time.
一样他以前没得到的东西
You mean like a weapon?
你是说某种武器？
No. That's enough. He's just a boy.
不是，够了，他还只是个孩子
You say more and you might as well induct him into the Order.
再多告诉他一点的话 你倒不如直接邀请他加入社团
Good. I want to join. If Voldemort's raising an army, then I want to fight.
很好啊，我很想加入 如果伏地魔在制造军团，那我也想战斗
Harry.
哈利
You are hereby expelled.
在整个威森加摩面前
Before the entire Wizengamot.
你已被驱逐
Trains. Underground.
是火车，而且在地下
Ingenious, these Muggles.
太聪明了，这些麻瓜
Here we are.
我们到了
I've never used the visitors' entrance before. Should be fun.
我从来没用过客用入口 应该蛮有趣的
Right. Good. I'll just get my Muggle money.
是的，很好 我只要拿些麻瓜的钱
Terrible. Lost a lot of Galleons trading on the potions market.
太可怕了 在药剂市场使用的大量加隆丢失
Daily Prophet, ladies and gentlemen. Anybody for Daily Prophet?
女士们，先生们，预言家日报 有谁要预言家日报的？
Dumbledore. Is he daft, or is he dangerous?
邓布利多 是愚蠢还是危险？
- Morning, Arthur. - Morning, Bob.
- 你好，亚瑟 - 你好，鲍勃
Interdepartmental memos.
部门间的备忘录
We used to use owls. Mess was unbelievable.
以前我们使用的是猫头鹰 那种混乱程度是无法想象的
Merlin's beard. Thank you, Kingsley.
天啊，谢谢，金斯莱
- They've changed the time of your hearing. - When is it?
- 他们更改了你的听证会时间 - 什么时候开始？
In five minutes.
五分钟后
Department of Mysteries.
神秘事务司
And I'm confident, minister, that you will do the right thing.
我确信，部长 你们该做出正确的决定
Yes, but we must be...
是的，但我们一定...
Remember, during the hearing, speak only when you're spoken to.
记住，在听证会上，不要私自开口
Keep calm. You've done nothing wrong.
别紧张，你没做错事
As the Muggles say, truth will out.
就像那些麻瓜所说的 真相一定会水落石出的
Yes?
是吗？
I'm not allowed in, I'm afraid.
恐怕我不能陪你进去了
Good luck, Harry.
祝你好运，哈利
Disciplinary hearing of the 12th of August...
八月十二日的纪律听证会
...into offenses committed by Harry James Potter...
犯罪方，哈利·詹姆·波特
...resident at Number 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.
家住萨里郡小文金镇贞女路四号
Interrogators: Cornelius Oswald Fudge, Minister of Mag...
质问者，康奈利·奥斯瓦尔德·福吉 魔法部
Witness for the defense.
辩方证人
Albus Percival Wulfric...Brian Dumbledore.
阿不思·珀西瓦尔· 伍尔弗里克·布赖恩·邓布利多
You got our message that the time and place of the hearing...
你收到我们的通知...
- ...had been changed, did you? - I must have missed it.
- 说审判改时间地点了？ - 我可能没留意到
But by a happy mistake, I arrived at the Ministry three hours early.
但幸运的是 我不小心提早了3小时到达魔法部
The charges?
控诉是？
The charges against the accused are as follows:
被告将面临以下控诉
"That he did knowingly...
他在清醒
...and in full awareness of the illegality of his actions...
以及知道自己违法行为的前提下
...produce a Patronus Charm...
使用了守护神魔咒
...in the presence of a Muggle."
并且是在一位麻瓜面前
- Do you deny producing said Patronus? - No, but...
- 你否认曾使用此魔咒吗？ - 不，但是...
And you were aware that you were forbidden to use magic outside school...
你是否了解17岁以下的巫师在校园范围外
- ...while under the age of 17? - Yes, I was, but...
- 是禁止使用魔法的？ - 是的，我知道，但是...
Witches and wizards of the Wizengamot...
威森加摩的众女巫巫师们
I was only doing it because of the Dementors.
我是为了驱赶摄魂怪
Dementors?
摄魂怪？
In Little Whinging?
在小文金镇？
That's quite clever.
很聪明
Muggles can't see Dementors, can they, boy?
麻瓜是看不到摄魂怪的 对吗，孩子？
- Highly convenient. - I'm not lying.
- 真是便捷啊 - 我没说谎
- There were two of them, and if I hadn't... - Enough.
- 那天有两个，如果我... - 够了
I'm sorry to interrupt what I'm sure would have been a very well- rehearsed story...
抱歉打断你的话 这确实是个很好的故事
...but since you can produce no witnesses of the event...
但既然你无法找到证人
Pardon me, minister, but as it happens, we can.
对不起，部长 就如同事情发生了一样，我们有证人
Please describe the attack.
请描述一下当时的情况
What did they look like?
他们长什么样子？
Well, one of them was very large and the other rather skinny.
一个块头很大，还有一个很瘦小
Not the boys. The Dementors.
不是那两个孩子，是摄魂怪
Oh, right, right. Well, big.
哦，是的，是的，嗯，很大
Cloaked. Then everything went cold...
穿着披风，一切都变得很冷
...as though all the happiness had gone from the world.
就像一切的欢乐都离这个世界远去了
Now, look here. Dementors don't just wander into a Muggle suburb...
听着，摄魂怪不可能迷路进入麻瓜的区域
...and happen across a wizard. The odds are astronomical.
而且还刚巧遇见了一个巫师 这个可能性太微小了
I don't think anyone would believe...
我想没人相信
...the Dementors were there by coincidence, minister.
那些摄魂怪是碰巧在那里的，部长
I'm sure I must have misunderstood you, professor.
我可能误解你了，教授
Dementors are, after all, under the control of the Ministry of Magic.
不管怎么说，摄魂怪是听命于魔法部的
And it's so silly of me, but it sounded for a moment as though...
可能是我太笨了 这听起来有一点像是
...you were suggesting that the Ministry had ordered the attack on this boy.
你认为是魔法部指示这次攻击行动
That would be disturbing indeed, Madam Undersecretary...
这确实很让人担忧，副部长女士
...which is why I'm sure the Ministry will be mounting a full- scale inquiry...
所以我相信魔法部一定会彻底调查
...into why the two Dementors were so very far from Azkaban...
为什么那两只摄魂怪会在离阿兹卡班 那么远的地方出现
...and why they mounted an attack without authorization.
并且在未被授权的情况下进行攻击
Of course, there is someone...
当然，有一个人
...who might be behind the attack.
极有可能是这件事的主谋
Cornelius, I implore you to see reason.
康奈利，求求你看清是非黑白
The evidence that the Dark Lord has returned is incontrovertible.
总总迹象表明，神秘人已经回来了 这是无法否认的
He is not back.
他没有回来
In the matter of Harry Potter...
有关哈利·波特一事
...the law clearly states...
法律上明显指出
...that magic may be used before Muggles in life- threatening situations.
在生命受到威胁时 可以破例在麻瓜面前使用魔法的
Laws can be changed if necessary, Dumbledore.
有必要时法律是可以更改的 邓布利多
Clearly. Has it become practice to hold a full criminal trial...
这很显然，现在连未成年巫师 违例使用魔法这种小事
...to deal with a simple matter of underage magic?
也值得进行刑事审判了？
Those in favor of conviction?
认为被告该受到处罚的
Those in favor of clearing the accused of all charges?
认为该撤除一切控诉的
Cleared of all charges.
撤除一切控诉
Professor.
教授
Padfoot. Are you barking mad?
大脚板，你疯了吗？
You'll blow the entire operation.
你会破坏整个行动的
Sirius, what are you doing here? If somebody sees you...
小天狼星，你为什么来这里？ 如果被人看到了...
I had to see you off, didn't I?
我得为你送行啊，不是吗？
What's life without a little risk?
而且，活着不冒点险怎么行？
I don't wanna see you get chucked back in Azkaban.
我不想看到你又被抓回阿兹卡班
Don't worry about me.
别担心我
Anyway, I wanted you to have this.
话说回来，我想给你这个
Original Order of the Phoenix.
凤凰社的前任成员
Marlene McKinnon.
马琳·麦金农
She was killed two weeks after this was taken.
她在拍这张照片后的两个星期被杀了
Voldemort wiped out her entire family.
伏地魔杀了她全家
Frank and Alice Longbottom.
弗兰克和艾丽斯·隆巴顿
Neville's parents.
纳威的父母
They suffered a fate worse than death, you ask me.
对我而言，他们的遭遇比死更惨
It's been 14 years.
都已经十四年了
And still a day doesn't go by I don't miss your dad.
但我还是每天想念着你爸爸
Do you really think there's going to be a war, Sirius?
你真的认为会有战争吗，小天狼星？
It feels like it did before.
这个感觉跟上次一样
You keep it.
留着吧
Anyway, I suppose you're the young ones now.
不管怎么说 你现在是年轻的救世主了
I'll see you at the train.
火车上见
Bye- bye, darling.
再见，亲爱的
I love you.
我爱你
Hold my hand, lovey.
牵住我的手，亲爱的
There they are. They're in the far carriage.
他们在那儿 他们在那边的车厢
Bye.
再见
I'm surprised the Ministry's still letting you walk around free.
真奇怪，魔法部竟然还让你 自由自在的到处跑
Better enjoy it while you can.
趁现在好好享受吧
I expect there's a cell in Azkaban with your name on it.
阿兹卡班那可是有个牢房在等着你
- What'd I tell you? Complete nutter. - Just stay away from me!
- 我跟你说什么来着？十足的疯子 - 最好离我远点！
It's only Malfoy.
只不过是马尔福
What'd you expect?
有什么好计较的？
Hi, guys.
嗨，大家好
- Hey, Neville. - Hey there, Neville.
- 嗨，纳威 - 嗨，纳威
What is it?
这是什么？
- What's what? - That. Pulling the carriage.
- 什么什么？ - 那个，在拉车的
Nothing's pulling the carriage, Harry.
没有东西在拉车，哈利
It's pulling itself, like always.
它们一向都是自己动的 像以前一样
You're not going mad.
你没发疯
I can see them too.
我也看得到他们
You're just as sane as I am.
你跟我一样正常
Everyone, this is Loony Love...
各位，这是卢娜·洛夫...
Luna Lovegood.
卢娜·洛夫古德
What an interesting necklace.
很有趣的项链
It's a charm, actually.
其实是个魔法
Keeps away the Nargles.
用来避蝻钩的
Hungry.
我饿了
I hope there's pudding.
希望有布丁吃
- What's a Nargle? - No idea.
- 蝻钩是什么？ - 不知道
Good evening, children.
晚上好，孩子们
Now, we have two changes in staffing this year.
这个学年，教员安排上有两个变化
We're pleased to welcome back Professor Grubbly- Plank...
大家欢迎格拉普兰教授回来
...who'll be taking Care of Magical Creatures...
她将负责神奇生物的课程
...while Professor Hagrid is on temporary leave.
而海格教授将和大家 短暂的分开一段时间
We also wish to welcome our new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher...
同时我们也要欢迎新的 黑魔法防御课老师
...Professor Dolores Umbridge.
多洛雷斯·乌姆里奇教授
And I'm sure you'll all join me in wishing the professor good luck.
我相信大家都会和我一起祝愿她好运
Now, as usual, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has asked me to remind you...
和往常一样，我们的监管师费尔齐先生 交代我提醒你们...
She was at my hearing. She works for Fudge.
她也参加了我的听证会 她是给福吉干活的
Thank you, headmaster, for those kind words of welcome.
谢谢，校长 感谢你的欢迎致词
And how lovely to see all your bright...
看着你们欢乐明朗的笑脸
...happy faces smiling up at me.
我感到无比幸福
I'm sure we're all going to be very good friends.
我敢肯定 我们将成为非常要好的朋友
- That's likely. - That's likely.
- 才怪 - 才怪
The Ministry of Magic has always considered...
魔法部向来...
...the education of young witches and wizards to be of vital importance.
对年轻巫师的教育工作给予高度重视
Although each headmaster...
虽然每一任校长
...has brought something new to this historic school...
为了这所历史悠久的学校的发展 都注入新鲜血液
...progress for the sake of progress must be discouraged.
但是这种做法并不值得提倡
Let us preserve what must be preserved...
让我们继承那些该继承的
...perfect what can be perfected...
完善那些需要完善的
...and prune practices that ought to be prohibited.
并剪除那些应该被禁止的实践
Thank you, Professor Umbridge. That really was most illuminating.
谢谢你，乌姆里奇教授 你的讲话为我们带来很大的启发
- Illuminating? What a load of waffle. - What's it mean?
- 启发？简直废话连篇 - 什么意思？
Magic is forbidden in the corridors...
走廊里禁止使用魔法...
It means the Ministry's interfering at Hogwarts.
意思是说，魔法部将开始干涉霍格沃茨
Dean, Seamus.
迪安，西莫
- Good holiday? - All right.
- 假期过得好么？ - 还行
Better than Seamus', anyway.
应该会比西莫的强
Me mum didn't want me to come back this year.
我妈妈今年不想让我回来
- Why not? - Let me see. Because of you.
- 为什么？ - 让我想想，是因为你
The Daily Prophet's been saying a lot of things about you and Dumbledore.
《预言家日报》上写了很多 关于你和邓布利多的事
What, your mum believes them?
什么，你妈妈相信《预言家日报》？
Nobody was there the night Cedric died.
塞德里克死掉的那晚，没有别人在场啊
I guess you should read the Prophet, then, like your stupid mother.
那你不如学你的蠢妈妈那样 看《预言家日报》好了
- Don't talk about my mother. - I'll have a go at anyone that calls me a liar.
- 别侮辱我妈妈 - 说我是骗子的人，我都会跟他过不去
- What's going on? - He's mad, is what's going on.
- 发生什么事？ - 他疯了，就这事
Do you believe the rubbish he's come out with about You- Know- Who?
你信不信他所谓的神秘人的鬼话？
Yeah. I do.
是的，我相信
Has anyone else got a problem with Harry?
还有谁对哈利有怀疑？
- You all right? - Fine.
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
Seamus was bang out of order, mate.
西莫满嘴胡话，伙计
- But he'll come through, you'll see. - I said, I'm fine, Ron.
- 他会知道真相的，我们等着好了 - 我说了我没事，罗恩
Right. I'll just leave you to your thoughts, then.
好吧，让你跟你的想法一起呆着吧
Harry.
哈利
Bring it over here. Over here.
拿过来，这边
Oh, go on, Seamus. Go on, get it.
哦，继续，西莫，快点，搞定它
Good morning, children.
早上好，孩子们
Ordinary Wizarding Level examinations.
中级巫师资格考试
O- W- Ls.
O- W- Ls
More commonly known as OWLs.
通常也被叫做“OWLs”
Study hard and you will be rewarded.
好好学习，你们就会通过
Fail to do so, and the consequences may be severe.
反之，后果就会很严重
Your previous instruction in this subject has been disturbingly uneven.
这门课先前的教科书 编写的参差不齐，让人不安
But you'll be pleased to know, from now on...
让人欣慰的是，从现在开始你们将..
...you will be following a carefully structured, Ministry- approved...
采用一套经过精心安排的...
...course of defensive magic. Yes?
经由魔法部批准的防御魔法课程
There's nothing in here about using defensive spells?
是否包括使用防御符咒的内容呢？
Using spells?
使用符咒？
Well, I can't imagine why you would need to use spells in my classroom.
在我的教室里还需要用符咒吗？
We're not gonna use magic?
连魔法都不会用到？
You'll be learning about defensive spells in a secure, risk- free way.
你们会在一种安全的 零风险的情况下学习防御符咒
What use is that? If we're attacked, it won't be risk- free.
如果我们受到袭击就不能叫做零风险 那这个还有什么用？
Students will raise their hands when they speak in my class.
在我的教室里，应该先举手再发言
It is the view of the Ministry...
魔法部认为
...that a theoretical knowledge will be sufficient...
理论知识的掌握
...to get you through your examinations...
就足以让你们顺利通过考试
...which, after all, is what school is all about.
而这，正是学校的意义所在
And how's theory supposed to prepare us for what's out there?
可是我们如何用“理论知识” 来武装自己去面对危险？
There is nothing out there, dear.
根本不存在什么危险，亲爱的
Who do you imagine wants to attack children like yourself?
你认为会有谁来袭击 像你一样的孩子呢？
Oh, I don't know. Maybe Lord Voldemort.
哦，我不知道，或许是伏地魔
Now, let me make this quite plain.
让我把这个问题说白了吧
You have been told...
有人告诉你们
...that a certain dark wizard is at large once again.
曾经有某个强大的黑暗巫师
- This is a lie. - It's not a lie. I saw him. I fought him.
- 这是一个谎言 - 不是谎言，我看到他了，还跟他对抗过
Detention, Mr. Potter.
课后留下来，波特先生
Cedric Diggory dropped dead of his own accord?
照你所说 塞德里克自己就这么死了？
Cedric Diggory's death was a tragic accident.
塞德里克·迪戈里的死是个悲惨的意外
It was murder. Voldemort killed him.
他是被杀的，是伏地魔杀了他
Enough!
够了！
Enough.
够了
See me later, Mr. Potter. My office.
一会儿来见我，波特先生 到我的办公室来
Come in.
请进
Good evening, Mr. Potter.
晚上好，波特先生
Sit.
坐
You're going to be doing some lines for me today, Mr. Potter.
我打算让你做一些抄写，波特先生
No, not with your quill.
不，不是用你的鹅毛笔
Going to be using a rather special one of mine.
而是用我这个特制的
Now...
现在
...I want you to write, "I must not tell lies."
我要你写: “我不可以说谎”
How many times?
多少遍？
Well, let's say for as long as it takes for the message to sink in.
嗯，一直写到你明白它的含义为止吧
You haven't given me any ink.
你没有给我墨水
Oh, you won't need any ink.
哦，你不需要墨水
Yes?
怎么了？
- Nothing. - That's right.
- 没什么 - 很好
Because you know, deep down...
因为你心里深知
...you deserve to be punished.
你应当受到惩罚
Don't you, Mr. Potter?
不是吗，波特先生？
Go on.
继续
- Skiving Snackboxes. - Sweets that make you ill.
- 切片零食 - 包得病糖果
Get out of class whenever you like.
帮你逃出教室，任何时候
Obtain hours of pleasure from unprofitable boredom.
想玩多久就玩多久，不会觉得无聊
Care for another?
要不要再来一个？
- I'm not asking you to write all of it for me. - Please.
- 又没让你帮我写全部 - 别说了
I've been busy studying for these stupid OWL exams.
我忙着准备这个该死的“OWLs”考试
I'll do the introduction. That's all.
我写序论好了，就这样
Hermione, you're honestly the most wonderful person I've ever met.
赫敏，你真是我见过的最让人赞叹的人
- And if I'm ever rude to you again... - I'll know you've gone back to normal.
- 如果我再对你无礼... - 那说明你恢复正常了
What's wrong with your hand?
你的手怎么了？
Nothing.
没什么
The other hand.
另一只手
- You've got to tell Dumbledore. - No.
- 你得告诉邓布利多 - 不
Dumbledore's got enough on his mind right now.
邓布利多自己就有够多烦心的事了
I don't want to give Umbridge the satisfaction.
更何况，我不想让乌姆里奇得逞
Bloody hell, Harry. The woman's torturing you.
天哪，那个女人是在折磨你呢
- Lf the parents knew about this... - I haven't got any of those, have I, Ron?
- 要是你的父母知道的话... - 我没有父母，不是吗，罗恩？
Harry, you've got to report this.
哈利，你得把这个事情上报
- It's perfectly simple. You're being... - No, it's not.
- 这不是明摆着吗，你被... - 不，不是这样的
Hermione, whatever this is, it's not simple.
赫敏，不论是什么，都不简单
You don't understand.
你们不会明白的
Then help us to.
那就让我们明白
Dear Padfoot...
亲爱的大脚板
...I hope you're all right.
希望你一切安好
It's starting to get colder here. Winter is definitely on the way.
这里已经开始变冷 冬天就要来了
In spite of being back at Hogwarts, I feel more alone than ever.
虽然已经回到霍格沃茨 我却感到前所未有的孤独
I know you, of all people, will understand.
我知道只有你会了解这种心情
Hello, Harry Potter.
你好，哈利·波特
- Your feet. Aren't they cold? - Bit.
- 你的脚，不觉得冻吗？ - 有一点
Unfortunately, all my shoes have mysteriously disappeared.
很不幸，我的鞋子都神秘失踪了
I suspect Nargles are behind it.
我怀疑是蝻钩干的
- What are they? - They're called Thestrals.
- 他们是什么？ - 他们被叫做夜骐
They're quite gentle, really, but people avoid them because they're a bit...
其实他们很善良的，可是人们都避开它们 只是因为它们有些...
Different.
不一样
But why can't the others see them?
可是为什么别人看不到它们？
They can only be seen by people who've seen death.
只有见过死亡的人才会看到他们
So you've known someone who's died, then?
那么，你认识的人里面有人死了？
My mum.
我妈妈
She was quite an extraordinary witch, but she did like to experiment...
她是个非凡的女巫 但是她很喜欢试验
...and one day, one of her spells went badly wrong.
有一天，她的符咒出了大差错
- I was 9. - I'm sorry.
- 我那时9岁 - 很抱歉
Yes, it was rather horrible.
是的，的确很可怕
I do feel very sad about it sometimes, but I've got Dad.
有时候我感到悲伤 不过我还有爸爸
We both believe you, by the way.
其实我们都相信你
That He- Who- Must- Not- Be- Named is back, and you fought him...
那个连名字都不能提的人又回来了 而你跟他争斗过
...and the Ministry and the Prophet are conspiring against you.
魔法部和《日报》 就合谋陷害你和邓布利多
Thanks. It seems you're about the only ones that do.
谢谢，我想你是唯一一个相信我的人
I don't think that's true.
我不这么认为
But I suppose that's how he wants you to feel.
但是我猜那正是他想要的结果
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Well, if I were You- Know- Who...
嗯，如果我是神秘人
...l'd want you to feel cut off from everyone else...
我也会让你觉得被所有人孤立
...because if it's just you alone...
因为如果只有你一个人
...you're not as much of a threat.
就构不成什么威胁
- Do you ever stop eating? - What? I'm hungry.
- 你就没有不吃的时候？ - 什么？我很饿啊
Harry.
哈利
Can I join you?
我可以坐下来吗？
Pardon me, professor, but what exactly are you insinuating?
对不起，教授 你到底想要试探什么？
I am merely requesting that when it comes to my students...
我只是希望你在对待学生的时候
...you conform to the prescribed disciplinary practices.
遵照学校现有的规定
So silly of me, but it sounds...
恕我愚钝
...as if you're questioning my authority in my own classroom...
不过听起来似乎你正在置疑 我在我自己的课堂所行使的权利
...Minerva.
米勒娃
Not at all, Dolores, merely your medieval methods.
完全不是，多洛雷斯 只不过是你古旧的教学方法
I am sorry, dear.
很抱歉，亲爱的
But to question my practices is to question the Ministry...
置疑我的教学方法等同于置疑魔法部
...and by extension, the minister himself.
甚至是置疑部长他本人
I am a tolerant woman...
我是一个宽容的女人
...but the one thing I will not stand for is disloyalty.
可是有一样事情是我所无法容忍的 就是不忠不信
Disloyalty.
不忠不信
Things at Hogwarts are far worse than I feared.
霍格沃茨存在的问题 比我预先所担心的要严重的多
Cornelius will want to take immediate action.
康奈利将会立即采取行动
(多洛雷斯·乌姆里奇已被任命为 霍格沃茨最高监察官)
What's happened to Dumbledore?
邓布利多怎么了？
Having already revolutionized...
黑魔法防御课的教学
...the teaching of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
进行了革命性的变革
...Dolores Umbridge will, as high inquisitor, have powers...
多洛雷斯·乌姆里奇将代表最高权利
...to address the seriously falling standards at Hogwarts School.
来治理日益衰退的霍格沃茨学校
Just one question, dear.
我只想问一个问题，亲爱的
You've been in this post how long, exactly?
你在这个职位上到底多久了？
You applied first for the Defense Against the Dark Arts post, is that correct?
你最先申请的是 黑魔法防御课教师一职？
Yes.
是的
But you were unsuccessful?
不过失败了？
Obviously.
显然
(学习期间不准放音乐  所有韦斯莱产品立即禁止使用  要时刻保持衣冠得体和礼貌的举止)
Could you please predict something for me?
你为我预言一下吗？
I'm sorry?
什么？
Move those mouths.
嘴张大些
One teensy little prophecy?
哪怕是一丁点的预言？
Pity.
可惜
No, wait. Wait, no. I think I do see something.
不，不，等等 我想我的确看到了一些...
Yes, I do. Something dark.
对，是黑暗
You are in grave danger.
你正在受到死亡的威胁
Lovely.
好极了
Cho. What's going on?
秋，发生什么事了？
It's Professor Trelawney.
是特里劳妮教授
Sixteen years I've lived and taught here.
我在这里教了16年
Hogwarts is my home.
霍格沃茨就是我的家
You can't do this.
你不能这么做
Actually, I can.
实际上，我可以
Something you'd like to say?
你有话想说吗？
Oh, there are several things I would like to say.
哦，有些事情我要说
There...
有些...
Professor McGonagall, might I ask you to escort Sybil back inside?
麦格教授 能请你将特里劳妮教授护送进去吗？
Sybil, dear. This way.
亲爱的西比尔，这边走
Thank you.
谢谢
Dumbledore, may I remind you that under the terms...
邓布利多，我想提醒你
...of Educational Decree Number 23, as enacted by the minister...
按照魔法部长执行的教育法令第二十三条
You have the right to dismiss my teachers.
你有权开除我的老师
You do not, however, have the authority to banish them from the grounds.
但是你无权驱逐他们
That power remains with the headmaster.
这个权力是属于校长的
For now.
目前为止
Don't you all have studying to do?
你们没功课做了吗？
Professor.
教授
Professor?
教授？
Professor Dumbledore. Professor!
邓布利多教授，教授！
Professor Dumbledore.
邓布利多教授
That foul, evil, old gargoyle.
污秽邪恶的老太婆
We're not learning how to defend ourselves. We're not learning how to pass our OWLs.
我们根本不在学习如何保护自己 也不是学习如何通过“OWLS”考试
She's taking over the entire school.
现在整个学校都在她手上了
Security has been and will remain the Ministry's top priority.
安全问题现在是魔法部的首要任务
Furthermore, we have convincing evidence...
此外 我们已经掌握到有力证据
...that these disappearances are the work...
这些失踪事件是由臭名昭著的
...of notorious mass murderer Sirius Black.
杀人惯犯小天狼星·布莱克所作
Harry.
哈利
Sirius.
小天狼星
- What are you doing here? - Answering your letter.
- 你在这儿干嘛？ - 回复你的信啊
You said you were worried about Umbridge. What's she doing?
你说你很担心乌姆里奇 她在做什么？
Training you to kill half- breeds?
训练你猎杀杂种？
- She's not letting us use magic at all. - Well, I'm not surprised.
- 她不让我们学习任何魔法 - 我一点也不感到惊讶
The latest intelligence is that Fudge doesn't want you trained in combat.
最新的情报是 福吉不想让你们接受战斗训练
Combat?
战斗？
What does he think, we're forming some sort of wizard army?
他什么意思？ 以为我们在建立“巫师军团”？
That's exactly what he thinks.
这正是他的想法
That Dumbledore is assembling his own forces to take on the Ministry.
邓布利多正私下建立军团，以对抗魔法部
He's becoming more paranoid by the minute.
他的妄想症越发严重了
The others wouldn't want me telling you this, Harry...
其他人不会告诉你这个，哈利
...but things aren't going at all well with the Order.
但是凤凰社里的事情不太妙
Fudge is blocking the truth at every turn...
福吉正在封锁消息
...and these disappearances are just how it started before.
之前的每次 也都是从失踪事件开始的
Voldemort is on the move.
伏地魔已经开始行动了
Well, what can we do?
我们该怎么办？
Someone's coming.
有人来了
I'm sorry I can't be of more help.
很抱歉我帮不了你太多
But for now, at least, it looks like you're on your own.
不过至少 现在看来你得孤军奋战了
He really is out there, isn't he?
他就在外面，对不对？
We've got to be able to defend ourselves.
我们一定要学会保护自己
And if Umbridge refuses to teach us how, we need someone who will.
如果乌姆里奇不肯教我们 我们就得找个愿意教的
Harry.
哈利
This is mad. Who'd wanna be taught by me?
这简直是发疯，谁会让我教啊？
I'm a nutter, remember?
我是个疯子，记得吗？
Look on the bright side: You can't be any worse than old toad face.
乐观点，你总不至于比那老巫婆还差劲
- Thanks, Ron. - I'm here for you, mate.
- 谢谢你，罗恩 - 我会坚决支持你，伙计
Who's supposed to be meeting us, then?
都有谁来？
Just a couple of people.
只有几个人
Lovely spot.
这地方不错
Thought it would be safer off the beaten track.
总比暴露行踪安全些
Matey, come back here.
美蒂，回来
Hi.
嗨
So you all know why we're here.
你们都知道我们为什么在这儿
We need a teacher.
我们需要一个老师
A proper teacher.
一个真正意义上的老师
One who's had experience defending themselves against the Dark Arts.
这个人需要具有对抗黑魔法的经验
- Why? - Why?
- 为什么？ - 为什么？
Because You- Know- Who's back, you tosspot.
因为神秘人又回来了，你个笨蛋
- So he says. - So Dumbledore says.
- 因为他这么说 - 邓布利多也这么说
So Dumbledore says because he says.
邓布利多这么说是因为他这么说
The point is, where's the proof?
问题是，证据在哪？
If Potter could tell us more about how Diggory got killed...
哈利可以告诉我们 究竟迪戈里是怎么死的
I'm not gonna talk about Cedric, so if that's why you're here, clear out now.
我不想再多谈塞德里克 如果你们是为了这个而来，请出去
Come on, Hermione. They're here because they think I'm some sort of freak.
我们走吧，赫敏 他们来这儿是因为觉得我是个疯子
Is it true you can produce a Patronus Charm?
你真的会守护神魔咒吗？
Yes.
是的
I've seen it.
我见过
Blimey, Harry. I didn't know you could do that.
天哪，哈利 我不知道你会这个呢
And he killed a basilisk, with the sword in Dumbledore's office.
他还在邓布利多的办公室里 用剑杀死了蛇怪呢
It's true.
这是真的
Third year, he fought off about a hundred Dementors at once.
三年级时，他独自跟几百个摄魂怪斗过
Last year, he really did fight off You- Know- Who in the flesh.
去年，他的确在电光石火之间 跟神秘人交战过
Wait.
等下
Look, it all sounds great when you say it like that...
你们这样说听起来真的很不错
...but the truth is, most of that was just luck.
可事实是，多数情况我都是靠运气而已
I didn't know what I was doing half the time. I nearly always had help.
半数时候我都手足无措 而且总有贵人相助
- He's just being modest. - No, Hermione, I'm not.
- 他是自谦 - 不，赫敏，我不是自谦
Facing this stuff in real life is not like school.
在现实生活中面对这些鬼怪 跟在学校里学习完全不一样
In school, if you make a mistake, you can just try again tomorrow.
在学校，如果你做错了 你可以明天重来一遍
But out there...
可是现实中
...when you're a second away from being murdered...
当死亡近在咫尺的时候
...or watching a friend die right before your eyes...
或者眼睁睁的看着你朋友被杀害
You don't know what that's like.
你们不了解那种感觉
You're right, Harry, we don't.
你说得对，哈利，我们不明白
That's why we need your help.
所以我们需要你的帮助
Because if we're going to have any chance at beating...
因为也许总有一天 我们得面对
...Voldemort...
伏地魔
He's really back.
他真的回来了
Right. First we need to find a place to practice...
对，首先我们得找个乌姆里奇
...where Umbridge won't find out.
找不到的地方练习魔法
- The Shrieking Shack. - It's too small.
- 尖叫棚屋 - 那里太小
- Forbidden Forest? - Not bloody likely.
- 禁林呢？ - 不可能
Harry, what happens if Umbridge does find out?
哈利，如果乌姆里奇发现了怎么办？
Who cares?
管她呢！
I mean, it's sort of exciting, isn't it, breaking the rules?
我是说，这个很刺激，违反校规
Who are you and what have you done with Hermione?
你是谁？你把赫敏怎么了？
Anyway, at least we know one positive thing that came from today.
无论如何，今天有件好事值得一提
What's that?
是什么？
Cho couldn't take her eyes off you, could she?
秋的视线一直跟着你转，不是吗？
Right. Over the next few days, we should each come up...
好吧，接下来的几天
...with a couple of possibilities of places we can practice.
我们分头找可以用来练习的场地
We've got to make sure, wherever it is, there's no chance she can find us.
最重要的是确保她找不到
Will do, Harry.
会找到的，哈利
All student organizations are henceforth disbanded.
所有学生组织立即解散
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
违令者，开除
Watch where you're going, Longbottom.
哪里去，隆巴顿？
You've done it, Neville. You found the Room of Requirement.
你成功了，纳威 你找到了“有求必应屋”
The what?
什么？
It's also known as the Come and Go Room.
这房间时有时无
The Room of Requirement only appears when a person has real need of it.
但只出现在真正有需要的人面前
And it's always equipped for the seeker's needs.
而且根据需要准备齐全
So say you really needed the toilet...
比方说我需要厕所
Charming, Ronald. But, yes, that is the general idea.
可爱的罗恩 不错，基本就是这样
It's brilliant. It's like Hogwarts wants us to fight back.
绝好的主意 就好像霍格沃茨要我们反击
Expelliarmus.
除你武器
I'm hopeless.
我没指望了
You're just flourishing your wand too much. Try it like this. Expelliarmus.
你只是甩棒太狠，这样试试 除你武器
You will please copy the approved text four times...
你们要抄写核准的课文四遍
...to ensure maximum retention.
以确保注意力集中
- There will be no need to talk. - No need to think's more like it.
- 你们不必讲话 - 其实是不必思考吧
- Expelliarmus. - Wands away.
- 除你武器 - 放下魔杖
Stunning is one of the most useful spells in your arsenal.
昏倒术是你武器库里最有用的武器
It's a wizard's bread and butter, really.
是魔法师们最常用的魔法
So come on, then, Nigel. Give it your best shot.
来吧，奈吉尔，尽你全力试试
Stupefy!
昏昏倒地！
Good. Not bad at all, Nigel. Well done.
很好，不错 奈吉尔，做得好
Don't worry. I'll go easy on you.
别担心，我们放点水
Thanks, Ronald.
谢谢，罗恩
- Come on, Ron. - Come on, Ron.
- 加油，罗恩 - 加油，罗恩
- You can do it. - Come on, Ron.
- 你能做到 - 加油，罗恩
- One Sickle. - You're on.
- 一颗包得病糖果 - 跟你赌了
Stupefy.
昏昏倒地
- Thank you. - Shut up.
- 谢谢 - 闭嘴
I let her do that. It's good manners, isn't it?
是我让她的，要有礼貌，不是吗？
It was completely intentional.
完全是有意的
(第82条学规: 全体学生必须 接受非法行为嫌疑的讯问)
Up you come. Would you like a cup of tea?
你上来 想来杯茶吗？
Now, focus on a fixed point and try again.
现在注意力集中一点 再试一次
Expelliarmus.
除你武器
Very good. Keep your concentration.
很好，保持注意力
Great.
很好
A little higher.
再高一点
I'm okay. I'm okay.
我还好，我没事
- Stupefy. - Stupefy.
- 昏昏倒地 - 昏昏倒地
Those wishing to join the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
有志于进入审判班学习的 作为额外奖励
...may sign up in the high inquisitor's office.
可以与高级检查官办公室签约
Diminuendo.
缩小咒
Working hard is important, but there's something that matters even more:
努力学习很重要 有些事情更重要
Believing in yourself.
那就是: 相信你自己
- Expelliarmus. - Levicorpus. Got it.
- 除你武器 - 倒挂金钟，成功了
Think of it this way.
相信你自己
Every great wizard in history has started out...
所有历史上伟大的魔法师
...as nothing more than what we are now: Students.
起步时并不比我们强，都是学生
If they can do it, why not us?
如果他们能做到，为什么我们不能？
- Stupefy. - Expelliarmus.
- 昏昏倒地 - 除你武器
Expelliarmus.
除你武器
Reducto.
粉身碎骨
- Expelliarmus. - Expelliarmus.
- 除你武器 - 除你武器
Expelliarmus.
除你武器
Fantastic, Neville. Well done, man.
完美，纳威 做得好
So that's it for this lesson.
课程要告一段落了
Now, we're not gonna be meeting again until after the holidays.
我们假期后再见
So just keep practicing on your own as best you can.
所以尽你们所能练习
And well done, everyone. Great, great work.
大家做得非常好 出色，非常非常出色
Well done, mate.
做得好，伙计
Thanks.
谢谢
See you after Christmas.
圣诞节后见
See you in the Common Room, Harry.
大厅见，哈利
- Thanks a lot, Harry. - No worries.
- 多谢了，哈利 - 别担心
- Thank you so much. - Not at all. Merry Christmas.
- 太感谢了 - 不客气，圣诞快乐
- Thank you, Harry. - Thank you. Merry Christmas.
- 谢谢，哈利 - 谢谢，圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas. - Have a good Christmas.
- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐
- Have a great Christmas, Luna. - We've been thinking.
- 圣诞快乐，露娜 - 我们在想
We could always slip Umbridge some Puking Pastilles.
我们可以给乌姆里奇的 点心里来点呕吐片
Or Fever Fudge. They give you massive, pus- filled boils...
或者是发烧的福吉 他们让你受那么多苦...
Sounds great, guys. Would you excuse me?
听来不错，伙计们 能借过吗？
Are you all right? I heard Umbridge gave you a rough time the other day.
你还好吗？ 我听说乌姆里奇对你很严苛
Yeah. I'm okay.
我很好
Anyway, it's worth it.
不管怎样，值得
It's just, learning all this...
只是，只是学着这些
...makes me wonder whether, if he'd known it...
让我想起，不知道他是否知道
Cedric did know this stuff.
塞德里克，塞德里克知道这些的
He was really good.
他非常厉害
It's just, Voldemort was better.
只是伏地魔更厉害一点
You're a really good teacher, Harry.
你真是个好老师，哈利
I've never been able to stun anything before.
我以前从来没有 击倒过任何东西
Mistletoe.
槲寄生（情人草）
Probably full of Nargles, though.
这可能也是蝻钩干的吧
What are Nargles?
蝻钩是什么？
No idea.
不知道
Well, how was it?
感觉如何？
Wet.
湿乎乎
I mean, she was sort of crying.
我的意思是她好像在哭
That bad at it, are you?
你水平不是那么差吧
I'm sure Harry's kissing was more than satisfactory.
哈利的吻肯定是很令人满意的
Cho spends half her time crying these days.
只不过是因为她这些日子经常哭
You'd think a bit of snogging would cheer her up.
亲亲她能让她高兴起来？
Don't you understand how she must be feeling?
你得明白她心里的感受
Well, obviously she's feeling sad about Cedric...
显然，她为塞德里克难过
...and confused about liking Harry and guilty about kissing him...
迷茫于对哈利的爱 又因为吻了哈利而内疚
...conflicted because Umbridge might sack her mum from the Ministry...
两种想法并存而矛盾冲突 害怕别人对她的看法
...and frightened of failing her OWLs because she's worrying about everything.
她又因为自己心事太多 害怕自己的OWLS考试可能会通不过
One person couldn't feel all that. They'd explode.
一个人有那么多感情会爆炸的
Just because you've got the emotional range of a teaspoon...
就因为你的情感 能力跟茶勺差不多？
Harry.
哈利
Voldemort may be after something.
伏地魔可能在搜寻什么
Something he didn't have last time.
他上次没有拿到的东西
Harry.
哈利
哈利！
In the dream, were you standing next to the victim...
在梦里，你是否站在受害者身边？
...or looking down at the scene?
还是俯视着现场？
Neither. It was like I...
都不是…就好象是
Will you please just tell me what's happening?
教授，请告诉我是怎么了
Everard, Arthur's on guard duty tonight.
埃弗拉，阿瑟今晚当班
Make sure he's found by the right people.
快去找人救他
- Sir. - Phineas.
- 先生！ - 菲尼亚斯
You must go to your portrait at Grimmauld Place.
你要去格里莫广场的画像
Tell them that Arthur Weasley is gravely injured...
告诉他们阿瑟·韦斯莱严重受伤
...and his children will be arriving there soon by Portkey.
孩子们很快会通过门钥匙过去
They've got him, Albus. It was close, but they think he'll make it.
他们找到了他 他差一点就完了，不过会好起来的
What's more, the Dark Lord failed to acquire it.
还有，黑魔头没拿到东西
Oh, thank goodness. Next we need to...
哦，太好了，下面我们要…
Look at me!
看着我！
What's happening to me?
我是怎么了
You wished to see me, headmaster?
你要见我，校长大人？
Oh, Severus. I'm afraid we can't wait. Not even till the morning.
西弗勒斯，恐怕我们不能等了 连天亮不能等
Otherwise, we'll all be vulnerable.
否则我们就危险了
It appears there's a connection...
看来黑魔头的意识
...between the Dark Lord's mind and your own.
跟你的是连在一起的
Whether he is, as yet, aware of this connection is, for the moment, unclear.
不过他是否了解这种联系 还是未定之数
Pray he remains ignorant.
希望他还没有发觉
You mean, if he knows about it, then...
你是说，如果他知道的话
- ...he'll be able to read my mind? - Read it, control it...
- 他可以读取我的心灵？ - 读取、控制
...unhinge it.
误导
In the past, it was often the Dark Lord's pleasure...
黑魔头过去很喜欢
...to invade the minds of his victims...
侵入受害者的心灵
...creating visions designed to torture them into madness.
炮制幻觉来折磨他们 把他们逼疯
Only after extracting the last exquisite ounce of agony...
直到榨干他们最后一丝痛苦
...only when he had them literally begging for death, would he finally...
让他们苦求一死
...kill them.
然后才杀了他们
Used properly, the power of Occlumency...
如果使用得当，锁心术
...will help shield you from access or influence.
可令你的心不受窥探或操控
In these lessons, I will attempt to penetrate your mind.
在课程里 我将要试图渗透你的心灵
You will attempt to resist.
你要尝试抵抗
Prepare yourself.
准备好！
Legilimens.
摄神取念！
Concentrate, Potter. Focus.
集中精力，波特，集中精力
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Here we go.
来了
Daddy's back.
爸爸回家了
Sit down, everybody, sit down. That's it. Now, presents.
坐下，大家坐下 现在发礼物
- And a nice big box for Ron. - Big box for you. And...
- 给罗恩的礼物 - 给你一个大家伙
Fred and George. Come on, open up.
哦，拿着吧
- I want to see your faces. - Yes.
- 打开吧，我要看看你们的表情 - 好的
- Try it on. - Thanks, Mum. It's perfect.
- 穿上试试 - 谢谢妈妈
- Just what he wanted, actually. - Yeah. Right. Thanks, Mum.
- 哦！完美！就是他想要的 - 呵呵，是的，谢谢妈妈
Come on, then, everybody. Let's clear this away.
大家过来这边
Oh, Harry, Harry.
哦，哈利，哈利
There you are.
你来了
- Happy Christmas. - Thank you.
- 圣诞快乐 - 谢谢
- Lovely to have you with us. - Thank you.
- 欢迎加入我们 - 谢谢
Now, Daddy. Pass that to Daddy.
给爸爸的，传给爸爸
- Thank you. - Has everybody got?
- 谢谢 - 大家都拿到了吗？
Fred? George?
弗雷德？乔治？
- Hermione. - A Christmas toast.
- 来吧 - 为圣诞干杯
To Mr. Harry Potter...
致哈利·波特先生
...without whom I would not be here.
没有他，我今天也不能在这里
- Harry. - Harry.
- 哈利 - 哈利
Harry.
哈利
That is delicious. I shall be needing some more of that.
噢，那个很好吃 给我再来点
Daddy, don't forget last Christmas.
爸爸，少吃点 别像上个圣诞节那样
I can't understand why you don't want to wear it, Ronald.
我不明白你为什么不愿穿
I look like a bloody idiot, that's why.
我穿了会像个傻子
No more than usual, Ron.
不会的
I don't know why...
我不知道为什么
Nasty brat, standing there as bold as brass.
肮脏的英国人厚颜地站在那里
Harry Potter, the boy who stopped the Dark Lord.
哈利·波特 阻止了黑魔头的男孩
Friend of Mudbloods and blood- traitors alike.
泥巴种跟叛种者的朋友
- Lf my poor mistress only knew... - Kreacher!
- 如果我可怜的小姐… - 克利切！
That's enough of your bile. Away with you!
你说的够多了 走开！
Of course, master.
当然，主人
Kreacher lives to serve the noble house of Black.
精灵活着就是为布莱克家族服务的
Sorry about that.
非常抱歉
He never was very pleasant, even when I was a boy.
他从来就不让人舒服 我小时就是这样
Not to me, anyway.
至少不会让我舒服
What, you grew up here?
怎么，你，你在这里长大
This is my parents' house.
这是我父母的房子
I offered it to Dumbledore as headquarters for the Order.
我把它捐给邓布利多 作为凤凰社的总部
About the only useful thing I've been able to do.
我只能做到这样了
This is the Black family tree.
这是布莱克家族的家谱
My deranged cousin.
我精神错乱的堂姐（贝拉特克里斯）
I hated the lot of them.
我恨他们很多人
My parents with their pure- blood mania.
我的父母对血统的纯正性很狂热
My mother did that after I ran away.
我出走以后我妈妈干的
Charming woman.
厉害的女人吧？
I was 16.
我那时16岁
Where did you go?
你去了哪里？
Round your dad's.
去你父亲那里
I was always welcome at the Potters'.
我总是在跟波特家的人工作
I see him so much in you, Harry.
我经常在你身上看到你父亲的影子，哈利
You are so very much alike.
你跟你父亲非常像
I'm not so sure.
我不敢确定
Sirius, when I was...
小天狼星，当我…
When I saw Mr. Weasley attacked, I wasn't just watching.
当我看到韦斯莱先生遇袭时 我不只是看到了
I was the snake.
我就是那条蛇
And afterwards, in Dumbledore's office...
后来在邓布利多的办公室
...there was a moment when I wanted to...
有那么一刹那，我想要，想要…
This connection between me and Voldemort.
我跟伏地魔之间的联系
What if the reason for it is that I am becoming more like him?
不管原因如何 我变得像他了
I just feel so angry all the time.
我时常感到愤怒
And what if, after everything that I've been through...
而且… 我经历了这么多事情
...something's gone wrong inside me? What if I'm becoming bad?
要是我内心出了岔子，怎么办？ 要是我变坏了，怎么办？
I want you to listen to me very carefully, Harry.
认真听我说，哈利
You're not a bad person.
你不是一个坏人
You're a very good person who bad things have happened to.
你是一个好人 只是遭遇了不幸而已
You understand?
你明白吗？
Besides, the world isn't split into good people and Death Eaters.
世界不是分为好人和坏人
We've all got both light and dark inside of us.
每个人内心都有光明和黑暗
What matters is the part we choose to act on.
真正重要的是我们如何选择
That's who we really are.
知道我们究竟是什么人
Harry, time to go.
哈利，该走了
When all this is over, we'll be a proper family.
等这一切结束 我们会成为一家人
You'll see.
到时候你就知道 我是不是正确的了
Come on.
去吧
Really?
真的？
Harry. Harry.
哈利！哈利！
Hagrid's back.
海格回来了
I'm sorry.
对不起
I will say this one last time.
我说最后一次
I'm ordering you to tell me where you've been.
我命令你告诉我 你去了那里
I told you. I've been away for me health.
我告诉过你了 我是因为健康理由离开
- Your health? - Yeah. Bit of fresh air, you know.
- 你的健康？ - 是，一点新鲜空气，你知道的
Oh, yes. As gamekeeper, fresh air must be difficult to come by.
哦，是啊，作为护林人 很难得到新鲜空气
If I were you, I shouldn't get too used to being back.
如果我是你，我就不会想着回来了
In fact, I mightn't bother unpacking at all.
可能连收拾都不需要
This is top- secret, right?
这是最高机密，对吧
Dumbledore sent me to parley with the giants.
邓布利多派我去跟巨人接触
Giants?
巨人？
You found them?
你找到他们了？
Well, they're not that hard to find, to be perfectly honest. They're so big, see?
说真的，巨人不是很难找 他们那么大
I tried to convince them to join the cause.
我试图劝说他们加入我们
But I wasn't the only one that was trying to win them over.
但游说的不只是我
- Death Eaters? - Yes.
- 食死徒 - 是的
Trying to persuade them to join You- Know- Who.
试图撺掇他们加入神秘人
- Did they? - I gave them Dumbledore's message.
- 他们同意了？ - 我给了他们邓布利多的口信
Suppose some of them remember he was friendly to them. I suppose.
想让他们之中能有人记得 邓布利多一直很善待他们
And they did this to you?
他们就是这样回答你的？
Not exactly, no.
不完全对
Oh, go on, you have it, then, you dozy dog.
啊，好吧好吧，给你 你个馋嘴的狗
It's changing out there.
外面正在发生变化
Just like last time.
就像上次一样
There's a storm coming, Harry.
风暴要来了，哈利
We'd all best be ready when she does.
等它来时我们最好做好准备
We have confirmed that 10 high- security prisoners...
我们已经证实
...in the early hours of yesterday evening did escape.
昨天晚上有十名重犯逃脱
And of course, the Muggle prime minister has been alerted to the danger.
魔法部长对此种危险深感警觉
We strongly suspect...
我们强烈地怀疑
...that the breakout was engineered...
此次越狱
...by a man with personal experience in escaping from Azkaban...
是由有从阿兹卡班 逃脱经验的人主持
...notorious mass murderer Sirius Black...
即小天狼星·布莱克
...cousin of escapee Bellatrix Lestrange.
逃脱的囚犯包括 贝拉特克里斯
Dumbledore warned Fudge this could happen.
邓布利多警告过他们
He's gonna get us all killed just because he can't face the truth.
他们不肯接受事实 会害的我们都送命的
Harry.
哈利！
I wanted to apologize.
我想要道歉
Now even me mum says the Prophet's version of things don't add up.
现在连我老妈都说 预言家日报的预言不再可信了
So, what I'm really trying to say is that I believe you.
我其实想说的是 我相信你
Neville?
纳威？
Fourteen years ago...
14年前
...a Death Eater named Bellatrix Lestrange...
一个叫贝拉特里克斯 莱斯特兰奇的食死徒
...used a Cruciatus Curse on my parents.
在我父母身上用了钻心咒
She tortured them for information...
她想尽办法折磨他们 想获得信息
...but they never gave in.
但他们从未屈服
I'm quite proud to be their son.
我为是他们的儿子感到骄傲
But I'm not sure I'm ready for everyone to know just yet.
但是我不确定 我有没有准备好让别人知道这个
We're gonna make them proud, Neville. That's a promise.
我们会让他们骄傲的，我保证
Make it a powerful memory, the happiest you can remember.
把它变成强大的记忆 最使你开心的事情
Allow it to fill you up. Keep trying, Seamus.
让它充满你 试试看，西莫
George, your turn now.
乔治，该你了
Expecto Patronum.
守护神咒！
A full- bodied Patronus is the most difficult to produce...
完整的守护神是最难做的
...but shield forms can also be equally useful against a variety of opponents.
但不完整的也可以 有效对付很多敌人
Wow, that was really good.
哇哦，不错
Fantastic, Ginny.
很棒啊！金妮
Just remember, your Patronus can only protect you for as long as you stay focused.
记住，守护神只有 在你专心致志时才有用
So focus, Luna.
专心，露娜
Think of the happiest thing you can.
想你最开心的事情
Expecto Patronum.
守护神咒！
- I'm trying. - I know. It's good.
- 我在试 - 嗯，别着急，再试试
This is really advanced stuff, guys. You're doing so well.
这个真的是很高深的魔法 你们都做的很棒
Expecto Patronum.
守护神咒！
I'll make short work of this.
我来一次搞定
Bombarda Maxima.
强力爆破咒
Get them.
把他们给我抓起来
Been watching them for weeks.
我用了数周
And see, "Dumbledore's Army"...
搜寻邓布利多的军队
...proof of what I've been telling you right from the beginning, Cornelius.
康奈利，这证明了我 一开始就告诉你的事情
All your fear- mongering about You- Know- Who...
你对神秘人的恐惧从不是真的
...never fooled us for a minute.
从来也没有骗到过我们
We saw your lies for what they were:
我们看穿了你的谎言
A smokescreen for your bid to seize control of the Ministry.
不过是你阴谋控制魔法部的烟雾而已
Naturally.
显然的事情
No, professor. He had nothing to do with it. It was me.
不，教授，这事跟他无关，都是我做的
Most noble of you, Harry, to shield me, but as has been pointed out...
哈利你试图掩护我 这是很高尚的
...the parchment clearly says "Dumbledore's Army," not "Potter's."
但正如部长所言，明明是邓布利多的军队 而不是波特的军队
I instructed Harry to form this organization.
我指示哈利成立该组织
And I, and I alone, am responsible for its activities.
我，只有我要为此负责
Dispatch an owl to the Daily Prophet.
向预言家日报发出消息
If we hurry, we should still make the morning edition.
如果我们快点的话 还能赶上晨版
Dawlish, Shacklebolt, you will escort Dumbledore...
多利士、沙克尔 你们带邓布利多
...to Azkaban...
去阿兹卡班
...to await trial for conspiracy and sedition.
准备以阴谋和教唆罪受审
I thought we might hit this little snag.
啊，我想过这个问题
You seem to be laboring under the delusion that I'm going to...
你好像以为我会
What was the phrase?
怎么说来着
Come quietly.
束手就擒
Well, I can tell you this:
我可以告诉你
I have no intention of going to Azkaban.
我没打算去阿兹卡班
Enough of this.
够了！
Take him.
抓住他！
Well, you may not like him, minister...
你可能不喜欢他，部长大人
...but you can't deny...
但是你不能否认
...Dumbledore has got style.
邓布利多很厉害
(多洛雷斯·珍妮·乌姆里奇取代邓布利多成为霍格沃茨校长)
Boys and girls are not permitted to be within eight inches of each other.
男生和女生不得 互相接近至8英寸以内
Those wishing to join the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
加入审讯小组的学生
Students will be submitted to questioning about suspected illicit activities.
将会针对所有违反纪律的行为进行询问
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
不服从的学生将会立刻被开除
Harry.
哈利！
You did everything you could. No one could win against that old hag.
你尽力了 但是那个老巫婆实在是太厉害了
Even Dumbledore didn't see this coming.
就算邓布利多也没预见到
Harry, if it's anyone's fault, it's ours.
哈利，如果说这是谁的错的话 那也应该是我们的错
Yeah, we talked you into it.
是啊，我们拉你下水的
Yeah, but I agreed.
但我同意了
I tried so hard to help, and all it's done is make things worse.
我很努力想要帮忙 但总是把事情弄的更糟
Anyway, that doesn't matter anymore.
现在也没所谓了
Because I don't want to play anymore. All it does is make you care too much.
我不想再继续下去了 越继续下去，我就关心的越深
And the more you care, the more you have to lose.
关心的越深 则失去的越多
- So maybe it's just better to... - To what?
- 也许我该… - 该怎么样？
To go it alone.
单干
Hagrid.
海格
Any idea where he's taking us?
他要带我们到哪里去啊？
Hagrid, why can't you just tell us?
海格，为什么你不能 直接告诉我们
I've never seen the centaurs so riled.
我从没见半人马们如此狂暴
And they're dangerous at the best of times.
不要靠近他们，他们现在很危险
The Ministry restricts their territory much more...
魔法部大大限制了他们的领地
...they'll have a full uprising on their hands.
他们很快要有暴动了
Hagrid, what's going on?
海格，到底怎么回事？
I'm sorry to be so mysterious, you three.
真抱歉我这么神秘，三位
I wouldn't be bothering you at all with it, but with Dumbledore gone...
我本来不想麻烦你们 可是邓布利多离开了
...l'll likely be getting the sack any day now.
看样子我也快要滚蛋了
And I just couldn't leave without telling someone about him.
我在走之前必须要告诉别人
Grawpy.
格洛普
Down here, you great buffoon.
在这边，大傻瓜
Grawpy.
格洛普
Brought you some company.
我给你带了几个朋友来
I couldn't just leave him, because...
我不能就这么离开他，因为
Because he's my brother.
因为他是我兄弟
Blimey.
啊？
Well, half brother, really.
其实是同母异父兄弟
He's completely harmless, just like I said. Little high- spirited, is all.
他很友善的，正如我说的一样 不过他还在学习
- Grawpy, that is not polite. - Hagrid, do something.
- 格洛普，礼貌点 - 海格，快想点办法啊
We talked about this. You do not grab, do you?
我们说过这个的 你不抓人的，对吧
That's your new friend, Hermione.
他们是你的朋友，格洛普！
Grawpy.
格洛普！
Grawp.
Put me down.
把我放下
Now.
马上！
You all right?
你还好吧？
Fine.
没事
Just needs a firm hand, is all.
就是要坚定一点
I think you've got an admirer.
你好像有个崇拜者了
You just stay away from her, all right?
你不要靠近她，好吧
He gets his own food and all.
他会自己找食物
It's company he'll be needing when I'm gone.
我离开后他需要有人陪着他
You will look after him, won't you?
你们会帮我照顾他的，对吧
I'm the only family he's got.
我是他唯一的亲人
Feeling sentimental?
多愁善感起来了？
- That's private. - Not to me.
- 那是隐私 - 对我来说不是
And not to the Dark Lord, if you don't improve.
如果你不努力一点的话 对黑魔头也不是
Every memory he has access to is a weapon he can use against you.
你任何的记忆 他都可以用作武器来对付你
You won't last two seconds if he invades your mind.
如果他侵入你的心灵 你连两秒钟都坚持不了的
You're just like your father.
你就像你的父亲
Lazy, arrogant.
懒惰、自负
- Don't say a word against my father. - Weak.
- 不许说我爸爸的坏话！ - 软弱
- I'm not weak. - Then prove it.
- 我不软弱！ - 那么证明自己
Control your emotions.
控制你的情绪
Discipline your mind.
克制你的心灵
Legilimens.
摄神取念！
Harry.
哈利！
Sirius.
小天狼星
I may vomit.
我想吐了
Stop it.
停下
Is this what you call control?
你管这个叫控制？
We've been at it for hours. If I could just rest.
我们练习几小时了 我需要休息
The Dark Lord isn't resting.
黑魔头没有休息
You and Black, you're two of a kind.
你和黑魔头，你们两个的意识混在一起
Sentimental children forever whining about how bitterly unfair your lives have been.
你这个令人失望的多愁善感的小子 只会苦涩地抱怨生活如何的不公平
Well, it may have escaped your notice, but life isn't fair.
你可能没有注意到 生活本来就是不公平的
Your blessed father knew that. In fact, he frequently saw to it.
你的父亲知道 实际上他经常炮制不公
- My father was a great man. - Your father was a swine.
- 我父亲是个伟大的人 - 你父亲是头猪
- Legilimens. - Protego.
- 摄神… - 守护神！
Come on, Moony, Padfoot.
来吧，莉莉
Snape. Expelliarmus.
斯内普! 除你武器
Nice one, James.
干得好，詹姆
- Dad. - Impedimenta.
- 爸爸 - 障碍咒
Snivellus Greasy. Snivellus Greasy.
斯内普，斯内普，斯内普
Right. Who wants to see me take off Snivelly's trousers?
好了，谁想看我脱掉斯内普的裤子？
Snivellus Greasy. Snivellus Greasy.
斯内普，斯内普
Enough.
够了
Your lessons are at an end.
你的课程结束了
L...
我…
Get out.
滚出去
- What's your name? - Michael.
- 你叫什么名字？ - 麦克尔
Your hand's gonna be fine, Michael.
你的手会好的，麦克尔
Yeah. It's not as bad as it seems. See?
没看上去那么糟吧，你看
It's fading already.
疤痕已经开始消了
You can hardly see ours anymore, and the pain stops after a while.
几乎看不到疤了 过会儿就不疼了
As I told you once before, Mr. Potter...
就像我之前和你说的，波特
...naughty children deserve to be punished.
必须惩罚调皮的孩子
You know, George...
知道吗，乔治
...l've always felt our futures lay outside the world of academic achievement.
我总觉得世上不只是读书而已
Fred, I've been thinking exactly the same thing.
弗雷德，我和你不谋而合
(安静  OWL考试  只准使用572号马力诺墨水)
All right, professor!
哦，教授，你好啊
Here you go.
给你看个好东西
Ready when you are.
我准备好了
I need that prophecy.
我需要那个预言球
You'll have to kill me.
那你不如杀了我吧
Oh, I will. But first, you will fetch it for me.
我会的，但你必须先帮我拿到它
Crucio.
钻心咒！
Sirius.
小天狼星
Harry, are you sure?
哈利，你确定？
I saw it. It's just like with Mr. Weasley.
我亲眼看见的 就和上次看到韦斯莱一样
It's the door I've been dreaming about.
和我几个月来梦到的门一样
I couldn't remember where I'd seen it before.
可我就是想不起来在哪儿见过
Sirius said Voldemort was after something.
小天狼星说过 伏地魔在找一样东西
Something he didn't have the last time, in the Department of Mysteries.
一个上次没有得到的东西 其实就在神秘事务司
Harry, please, just listen.
哈利，你听我说
What if Voldemort meant for you to see this?
万一这是伏地魔故意让你看到的幻影呢？
What if he's only hurting Sirius because he's trying to get to you?
他伤害小天狼星的唯一目的是想逼你现身
What if he is? I'm supposed to just let him die?
那万一这是真的呢？ 我就这么袖手旁观？
Hermione, he's the only family I've got left.
赫敏，他是我唯一的亲人了
What do we do?
我们该怎么办
We'll have to use the Floo Network.
我们得用壁炉通道网络
Umbridge has the chimneys under surveillance.
邓布利多说烟囱都被监视了
Not all of them.
有一个没有
Alohomora.
开门咒
Alert the Order if you can.
你们想办法警告凤凰社
- Are you mental? We're going with you. - It's too dangerous.
- 你疯了？我们要跟你一起去！ - 那太危险了
When are you going to get it into your head? We're in this together.
你脑子里都在想什么？ 这是我们大家的事
That you are.
说得没错
Caught this one trying to help the Weasley girl.
他们在帮他的忙
You were going to Dumbledore, weren't you?
你们要去找邓布利多，是不是？
- No. - Liar.
- 不是的 - 撒谎！
- You sent for me, headmistress? - Snape, yes.
- 你叫我，乌姆里奇教授？ - 斯内普，是的
The time has come for answers, whether he wants to give them to me or not.
该让他们说实话了 不管他们愿不愿意
Have you brought the Veritaserum?
你把坦白剂带来了吗？
I'm afraid you've used up all my stores interrogating students.
很遗憾你审讯学生时全用光了
The last of it on Miss Chang.
最后一份用在了张小姐身上
Unless you wish to poison him...
除非你想对他下毒
And I assure you, I would have the greatest sympathy if you did.
如果你真要下的话 我表示真挚的同情
I cannot help you.
但我帮不了你
He's got Padfoot.
大脚板在他手上
He's got Padfoot at the place where it's hidden.
大脚板被抓去他藏身的地方了
Padfoot? What is Padfoot? Where what is hidden?
大脚板？大脚板是什么？
What is he talking about, Snape?
他在说什么，斯内普？
No idea.
不知道
Very well.
好吧
You give me no choice, Potter.
算了，这是你逼我的
As this is an issue of Ministry security...
这事关魔法部安全守则
...you leave me with...
你逼得我
...no alternative.
别无选择
The Cruciatus Curse ought to loosen your tongue.
克里斯塔咒应该能让你张口
That's illegal.
那是违法的
What Cornelius doesn't know won't hurt him.
只要康奈利不知道就行
Tell her, Harry!
告诉他，哈利！
Tell me what?
告诉我什么？
Well, if you won't tell her where it is...
你不告诉她那东西的位置
...I will.
我会的
Where what is?
什么东西？在哪里？
Dumbledore's secret weapon.
邓布利多的秘密武器
How much further?
还有多远？
Not far.
就快到了
It had to be somewhere students wouldn't find it accidentally.
必须藏在学生不容易找到的地方
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Lmprovising.
随机应变
Well?
好了
Where is this weapon?
武器在哪儿？
There isn't one, is there?
根本就没有这东西，是不是？
You were trying to trick me.
你们在唬弄我
You know...
你们
...I really hate children.
我真的很讨厌孩子
You have no business here, centaur. This is a Ministry matter.
这不管你们的事，人头马 这是魔法部的事务
Lower your weapons.
放下武器！
I warn you, under the law, as creatures of near- human intelligence...
我警告你们 在法律上，具有近似人类智力的生物…
Protego.
守护神！
How dare you?
放肆！
Filthy half- breed.
肮脏的杂种！
Incarcerous.
禁锢咒！
Please. Please stop it. Please.
求你了，快住手！
Now, enough. I will have order.
不够！我要建立秩序！
You filthy animal.
肮脏的畜牲！
Do you know who I am?
你知道我是谁吗？
Leave him alone. It's not his fault.
放过他！不是他的错！
No, he doesn't understand.
不要，他不明白
Potter, do something. Tell them I mean no harm.
波特，想想办法，告诉他们 我对他们没恶意
I'm sorry, professor.
对不起，教授
But I must not tell lies.
我不可以说谎
What are you doing?
你们干什么？
I am Senior Undersecretary Dolores Jane Umbridge.
我是魔法部资深副部长 多洛雷斯…
Let me go!
放开我！
Thank you, Grawp.
谢谢你，格洛普
Hermione. Hermione, Sirius.
赫敏，赫敏，小天狼星！
- How'd you get away? - Puking Pastilles. It wasn't pretty.
- 你们怎么逃出来的？ - 呕吐糖果，不好玩
Told them I was hungry, wanted some sweets.
我说我饿了，想吃点甜点
They told me to bugger off and ate the lot themselves.
当然他们抢走了糖盒 然后就全吃下去了
That was clever, Ron.
你太聪明了，罗恩
- Has been known to happen. - It was brilliant.
- 我知道肯定是那样 - 简直是天才
So how are we getting to London?
好了，我们要怎么去伦敦？
Look, it's not that I don't appreciate everything you've done, all of you...
听着，我不是不感谢 大家为我做的一切
...but I've got you into enough trouble as it is.
但…我已经给大家惹了够多麻烦了
Dumbledore's Army's supposed to be about doing something real.
邓布利多军团不是徒有虚名吧
Or was that all just words to you?
还是你觉得我们很没用？
Maybe you don't have to do this all by yourself, mate.
或许这次不用自己一个人去做了，伙计
So how are we going to get to London?
那我们要怎么去伦敦？
We fly, of course.
当然是飞过去了
Department of Mysteries.
神秘事务司
This is it.
就是这里了
92, 93
Ninety-two, Ninety-three.
Ninety-four.
Ninety-five.
- He should be here. - Harry.
- 他应该在这里 - 哈利
It's got your name on it.
这上面有你的名字
The one with the power to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches.
拥有征服黑魔头能量的人走近了
And the Dark Lord shall mark him as his equal...
黑魔头标记他为其劲敌
...but he shall have power the Dark Lord knows not.
但是他拥有黑魔头所不了解的能量
For neither can live while the other survives.
只有一个能生存下来
Harry.
哈利
Where's Sirius?
小天狼星在哪儿
You know, you really should learn to tell the difference between dreams...
呃，你真的应该学会 去区别梦境
...and reality.
和现实
You saw only what the Dark Lord wanted you to see.
你只能看见黑魔头想让你看见的东西
Now, hand me the prophecy.
把预言球交出来
If you do anything to us, I'll break it.
你敢动我们，我就砸碎预言球
He knows how to play.
他还挺机灵的
Itty, bitty baby.
漂亮可爱的娃娃
Potter.
波特
Bellatrix Lestrange.
贝拉特里克斯·莱斯特兰奇
Neville Longbottom, is it? How's Mum and Dad?
纳威·隆巴顿？ 你父母怎么样了？
Better, now they're about to be avenged.
很好，因为马上就可以为他们报仇了
Now, let's everybody just calm down...
让我们大家冷静下来
...shall we?
好吗？
All we want is that prophecy.
我们只想要那个预言球
Why did Voldemort need me to come and get this?
为什么伏地魔要 我自己来这里拿这东西？
You dare speak his name?
你竟敢直呼他的名字？
You filthy half- blood!
你这肮脏的杂种
It's all right. He's just a curious lad, aren't you?
算了，他只是个好奇的孩子罢了 是不是？
Prophecies can only be retrieved by those about whom they are made.
只有应时而生的人 才能找到预言球
Which is lucky for you, really.
你是在太幸运了
Haven't you always wondered...
你难道一直没想过
...what was the reason for the connection between you and the Dark Lord?
为什么你会与黑魔头产生如此强烈的共鸣？
Why he was unable to kill you...
为什么他
...when you were just an infant?
没有在你还是婴儿的时候杀了你？
Don't you want to know the secret of your scar?
你不想知道那伤疤的秘密吗？
All the answers are there, Potter, in your hand.
答案全在那里 波特，在你手里
All you have to do...
你只要
...is give it to me.
把它给我就行了
Then I can show you everything.
我会把一切都告诉你
I've waited 14 years.
我等了14年
I know.
我知道
I guess I can wait a little longer. Now. Stupefy.
我想我再等一阵子也无所谓，攻击！
Stupefy.
昏昏倒地！
Levicorpus.
倒挂金钟！
Petrificus Totalus.
统统石化！
Well done, Neville.
干得好，纳威
Stupefy.
昏昏倒地！
- Stupefy. - Stupefy.
- 昏昏倒地！ - 昏昏倒地！
Stupefy.
昏昏倒地！
Reducto.
粉身碎骨！
Get back to the door.
回出口！
Department of Mysteries. They got that bit right, didn't they?
神秘事务司 看来我们还真找对地方了
The voices.
那声音
Can you tell what they're saying?
能听见在说什么吗？
There aren't any voices, Harry.
这里哪里有什么声音
Let's get out of here.
我们快点离开这里
I hear them too.
我也听到了
Harry, it's just an empty archway.
哈利，那只是扇空的拱门
Please, Harry.
快点，哈利
Get behind me.
到我身后来！
Did you actually believe...
你真的相信…
...or were you truly naive enough to think...
还是你单纯的以为
...that children stood a chance against us?
你们这群孩子能打赢我们？
I'll make this simple for you, Potter.
我还是开门见山吧，波特
Give me the prophecy now...
交出预言球
...or watch your friends die.
不然就看着你的朋友们死去
Don't give it to him, Harry.
别给他，哈利
Get away from my godson.
离我的孩子远一点
Now, listen to me. Take the others and get out of here.
听我说，我要你带你的朋友们离开这里
What? No, I'm staying with you.
什么？不，我要和你在一起
You've done beautifully.
你已经干得很好了
Now, let me take it from here.
剩下的就交给我吧
Black.
布莱克
Expelliarmus!
除你武器！
Nice one, James.
干得好，詹姆
Avada Kedavra.
索命咒
No. No.
不！不！
I killed Sirius Black.
我杀了小天狼星·布莱克
- You coming to get me? - Crucio.
- 你来追我啊 - 钻心咒
You've got to mean it, Harry.
你必须杀了她，哈利，你要下定决心
She killed him. She deserves it.
她杀了他，她活该
You know the spell, Harry.
你会用那个咒语的，哈利
Do it.
杀了她！
So weak.
太懦弱了
It was foolish of you to come here tonight, Tom.
我就猜到你今晚会出现，汤姆
The Aurors are on their way.
凤凰社的人就快到了
By which time I shall be gone, and you...
届时我早就走了，而你
...shall be dead.
也活不成
You've lost, old man.
你输了，老骨头
Harry.
哈利
So weak.
没用
So vulnerable.
脆弱
Look at me.
看着我
Harry, it isn't how you are alike.
哈利，你跟他是否相像并不重要
It's how you are not.
你跟他的不同才重要
Harry?
哈利？
You're the weak one...
你才是懦弱的人
...and you'll never know love or friendship.
你从来不懂得爱 不懂得友情
And I feel sorry for you.
我可怜你
You're a fool, Harry Potter.
你错了，哈利·波特
And you will lose everything.
你会失去一切的
He's back.
他回来了
(邓布利多，波特被澄清)
(魔法部长将辞职？)
(乌姆里奇停职 准备接受调查)
(神秘人归来)
(霍格沃茨校长复职)
I know how you feel, Harry.
我知道你的感受，哈利
No, you don't.
不，你不知道
It's my fault.
都是我的错
No, the fault is mine.
不，是我的失职
I knew it was only a matter of time...
我明知你和伏地魔产生共鸣
...before Voldemort made the connection between you.
是早晚的事
I thought by distancing myself from you, as I have done all year...
我以为疏远你，他就不会这么快下手
...he'd be less tempted, and therefore you might be more protected.
那样就能保护你
The prophecy said:
预言球说
"Neither one can live while the other one survives."
“只有一个生存下来”
It means one of us is gonna have to kill the other, in the end.
是不是，我和他最终一定要杀死对方？
Yes.
是的
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不早告诉我？
For the same reason you tried to save Sirius.
和你救小天狼星是一个理由
The same reason your friends saved you.
还有你朋友救你的理由也是一样的
After all these years, after all you've suffered...
你吃了这么多年的苦
...I didn't want to cause you any more pain.
我不想再让你痛苦了
I cared too much about you.
我太在乎你了
How come you're not at the feast?
你怎么没去参加离校宴会
Lost all my possessions. Apparently people have been hiding them.
我的东西都丢了 好像有人把它们藏起来了
That's awful.
那太糟了
Oh, it's all good fun.
不，没事的
But as it's the last night, I really do need them back.
不过今晚是学期结束，我要打包 我得把他们都找回来
Do you want any help finding them?
要帮忙一起找吗？
I'm sorry about your godfather, Harry.
我为小天狼星的过世感到遗憾
Are you sure you don't want any help looking?
你确定你不需要帮忙？
That's all right.
不用了
Anyway, my mum always said...
再说，我妈以前经常说
...the things we lose have a way of coming back to us in the end.
失去的东西总会找到方法回来的
If not always in the way we expect.
虽然回来的方式和我们想象的总有些出入
Think I'll just go have some pudding.
我想我还是先去吃点布丁
I've been thinking about something Dumbledore said to me.
我一直在想邓布利多对我说过的话
What's that?
是什么？
That even though we've got a fight ahead of us...
虽然有一场艰苦的战斗等着我们
...we've got one thing that Voldemort doesn't have.
但我们有一样伏地魔没有的东西
Yeah?
是吗？
Something worth fighting for.
一样值得战斗的东西